<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The CodeMeta Project</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The CodeMeta Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Agenda</title>
      <link>/agenda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/agenda/</guid>
      <description>CodeMeta Workshop Venue and logistics  Portlant Paramount Hotel, Friday &amp;amp; Saturday  Coffee at 8am, Lewis Room  Sunday Force16 Workshop  OHSU Collaborative Life Science Building, Rooms TBD   Background materials and links  CodeMeta Web Site NIH Software Discovery report CodeMeta Github repo Software Metadata Crosswalk Guidelines for Persistently Identifying Software Using DataCite  Goals  Consensus cross walk table JSON-LD draft schema Consensus on software metadata  Outline of journal article   April 15 Portland Paramount Hotel, Lewis Room</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codemeta Terms</title>
      <link>/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/terms/</guid>
      <description>Terms from Schema.org Recognized properties for CodeMeta Code includes the following terms from https://schema.org:
  Property Type Description     codeRepository URL  Link to the repository where the un-compiled, human readable code and related code is located (SVN, github, CodePlex).   programmingLanguage ComputerLanguage or Text The computer programming language.   runtimePlatform Text  Runtime platform or script interpreter dependencies (Example - Java v1, Python2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Codemeta Workshop</title>
      <link>/workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workshop/</guid>
      <description>April 15 - 17 2016 Portland, Oregon The Future of Software Metadata Agenda 
 The CodeMeta Project Workshop The CodeMeta project does not seek to create yet another standard. Rather, we&amp;rsquo;re aiming to create a crosswalk table between standards already in use &amp;ndash; think of this as a Rosetta stone of software metadata. Beginning in an Open Science Code-fest discussion lead by Abby Mayes and now thanks to a generous NSF EAGER Grant to Carl Boettiger (UC Berkeley) &amp;amp; Matt Jones (NCEAS &amp;amp; UC Santa Barbara), we will bring together leaders of software and data repositories with academic researchers to develop this crosswalk table for software metadata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crosswalk for R Package DESCRIPTION file</title>
      <link>/crosswalk/r-description/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/crosswalk/r-description/</guid>
      <description>The following table displays the crosswalk mapping of terms from the R package DESCRIPTION file to codemeta properties.
  Property R Package Description    codeRepository URL  creator [cre] Author  dateCreated -  dateModified -  datePublished Date  editor -  license License  description Description  name Package  url URL  depends Depends, SystemRequirements  suggests Suggests  maintainer Maintainer  licenseId License  issueTracker BugReports  givenName givenName  familyName familyName  email email    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examples</title>
      <link>/examples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/examples/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Codemeta JSON-LD Representation</title>
      <link>/jsonld/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/jsonld/</guid>
      <description>The JSON-LD Context File CodeMeta properties can be serialized in JSON-LD by referencing the context file: &amp;quot;@context&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;https://doi.org/10.5063/SCHEMA/CODEMETA-1.0&amp;quot;. CodeMeta properties are built on and extend software properties from https://schema.org. A list of all properties provided by the current CodeMeta context file can be found on the terms page.
Aside from the use of @context, codemeta JSON-LD looks like any other json metadata record, and can be easily written by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Cases</title>
      <link>/use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/use-cases/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>